<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour Guide App</string>
    <string name="hello_friends_nwelcome_to_varna">Hello Friends,  \nWelcome to Varna!!!</string>
    <string name="enter">Enter</string>
    <string name="museums">Museums</string>
    <string name="landmarks">Landmarks</string>
    <string name="shopping">Shopping</string>
    <string name="parties">Parties</string>
    <string name="main_activity">Main Activity</string>
    <string name="categories">Categories</string>
    <string name="archaelogical_museum_name">Archaelogical Museum</string>
    <string name="arch_museum_work_times">10AM–5PM</string>
    <string name="archaelogical_museum_info">"One of the largest museums in Bulgaria, it features 2,150 m²
        of exhibition area and displays objects from the prehistoric, Thracian, Ancient Greek and Ancient
        Roman periods of the region's history, as well as from the times of the medieval Bulgarian and Byzantine
        Empires, the Ottoman rule and the Bulgarian National Revival (including about 900 medieval and Revival icons).
        The Museum's arguably most celebrated exhibit is the Gold of Varna, the oldest gold treasure in the world,
        excavated in 1972 and dating to 4600\-4200 BCE, which occupies three separate exhibition halls."</string>
    <string name="naval_museum_name">Naval Museum</string>
    <string name="naval_museum_work_times">10AM–6PM</string>
    <string name="naval_museum_info">"The museum visitors can see original ancient anchors and shop remnants,
        found on the bottom of the Black Sea; ship head decorations; uniforms of seamen and officers.
        Desk models show the diversity of the ship collection of the naval and the commercial fleet in various periods.
        Maritime flags, torpedoes, optical devices of lighthouses from the Bulgarian shores, medals, etc. are presented.
        Apparatuses and instruments show the complexity of the specifics of naval professions such as navigation and shipbuilding."</string>
</resources>
